Preliminary Inventory of the Committee on the Present Danger records
Hoover Institution Archives
- CPD 1980 Enhanced Defense Budget (Folder 199)
- 6:30 Club Action on SALT II Compliance, contains an op-ed by Trachtenberg refused by New York Times on Reagan's decision to abide by SALT II and a statement by CPD on this decision (Folder 200)
- Nitze letter complaining to the Washington Post about an article on the poll on SALT II materials (Folder 200)
- CPD Statements on ICBM Vulnerability, MX (Folder 200)
- Loose material, including a letter from Trachtenberg to the Washington Post complaining the CPD Strategic Defense Initiative and Geneva poll has not been reported, 1985 (Folder 200)
- CPD (Folder 200)
- P and S Poll Oct. 1985 (Folder 200)
- CPD P and S Press Conference, 27 August 1986 (Folder 201)
- CPD P and S Press Conference, 20 August 1986 (Folder 201)
- Poll, contains material on April 1987 on Strategic Defense Initiative, Defense spending, and other (2 folders) (Folder 201)
- P and S Poll, May 1988. contains material related to CPD 1988 poll, Press Release 26 May 1988, and a Washington Post column by Norman Podhoretz (Folder 202)
- CPD 1987 poll materials, and Press Release 30 November 1987 including a note by Suzanne Crow on the "Jeane Kirkpatrick questions" (Folder 202)
- Press clippings and specific undisclosed questions on a possible Jeane Kirkpatrick nomination as vice-presidential candidate on the Republican ticket in 1988. (Folder 202)
- CPD Future Pamphlet on SALT Hearings (Folder 202)
- CPD PAPER: "Our Stand on SALT II" (Folder 202)
- Current News Loose issues (Folder 202)
- Current News Loose issues (Folder 203)
- articles on the military, especially the JCS, under Reagan (Folder 204)
- Reagan administration-JCS (Folder 204)
- Selected Statements (Folder 204)
- Rostow correspondence, 1987-1992. Includes a letter sent by Richard Nixon in August 1987 congratulating for his New York Times op-ed piece on INF dangers and speeches by Rostow on USSR in 1987 (Folder 205)
- Rostow correspondence, 1981-1986. Includes a letter sent by President Reagan (Folder 206)
- Rostow correspondence and memos sent during the Reagan administration transition on people and issues, 1979-1981 (Folder 207)
- Rostow correspondence, 1978-1979 (Folder 208)
- Magazines (Folder 209)
- CPD material, including advertizing for Alerting America (Folder 209)
- [the following boxes apparently come from David Trachtenberg papers] (Folder 210)
- Loose material by other think tanks (Folder 210)
- Where we stand on arms control, press release and booklet, CPD (Folder 210)
- Why the Soviet Union Wants SALT II booklet by Richard Pipes, 17 September 1979 (Folder 210)
- Defense for Everyone Edward Teller statement (2 pages), 1 Oct 1986 (Folder 210)
- Is SALT II a Fair Deal for the United States? booklet by Paul H. Nitze, 16 May 1979 (Folder 211)
- People opposed to SALT articles (Folder 211)
- Loose similar materials (Folder 211)
- Anti-Defence group listings (Folder 211)
- Arms Control Today (Folder 211)
- American Security Council and the Coalition for Peace through Strength (Folder 211)
- Americans for SALT materials, including letters of support by Warnke and Alan Cranston addressed to Clark Clifford (Folder 211)
- American Committee on E-W Accord and the American Committee on U.S.-Soviet relations materials, articles and interviews by Kennan and issues of East-West Outlook and New Outlook (Folder 212)
- ACCESS (Folder 212)
- AFA (Folder 212)
- AFL-CIO (Folder 212)
- Foreign organizations, media projects, and conferences (Folder 213)
- ABA Conference, 27-28 June 1988 (Folder 213)
- The day after ABC, 1 Nov 1983 (Folder 213)
- Atlantic Council (Folder 213)
- CATO (Folder 213)
- The Defense of the United States CBS Reports (Folder 214)
- Technology transfer (Folder 214)
- Tech Transfer Legislative File (Folder 215)
- Technology transfer (2 folders) (Folder 215)
- Geneva Convention, warfare (Folder 215)
- The Effects of Nuclear War, ACDA (Folder 215)
- The Effects of Nuclear War, OTA (Folder 215)
- Human rights (Folder 216)
- Loose materials (Folder 216)
- Failures of Glosnost and Perestroika (Folder 216)
- Sino-soviet border and Siberia (Folder 216)
- Intelligence (Folder 217)
- Intelligence (Folder 218)
- Military Balance, 1991. Contains material on U.S.-Soviet military balance, including a press release (circa November 1991), and letters on the text-some quite critical by John P. Roche (Folder 219)
- "Has America Caught up? The U.S.-Soviet Military Balance," 1991 (Folder 219)
- Fundraiser, 1992 (Folder 219)
- 15TH Annual meeting (Folder 219)
- CPD references, projects (Folder 219)
- CPD, 1979-1980. Contains a $185,000 proposal to the Samuel Roberts Noble Foundation for a continuing study on U.S.-Soviet Military balance, 14 Feb 1980 (Folder 219)
- Annual meeting, 1990 (Folder 220)
- Fundraiser, 1990 (Folder 220)
- Executive Committee, 9 Jan 1990. Includes draft statement by Rostow, informally titled E.V.R. "Second Manifesto," on CPD future in the new era (Folder 220)
- Annual Meeting, 9-10 Nov 1989 (Folder 220)
- Executive Committee, 17 Mar 191989 (Folder 220)
- 12th Annual Mtg. 10-11 Nov 1988 (Folder 220)
- Executive Committee, 28 Jan 1988 (Folder 220)
- Rostow correspondence (Folder 220)
- 11th Ann. Mtg. 5-6 November 1987 (Folder 221)
- Executive Committee, 22 May 1987 (Folder 221)
- Executive Committee, 12 Dec 1986 (Folder 221)
- 10th Annual Meeting 6-7 Nov 1986 (Folder 221)
- CPD October Conference (Folder 221)
- Executive Committee, 31 July 1986. Contains a draft "Statement on a tax increase for defense," (Folder 221)
- Executive Committee, 18 Apr -1986 (Folder 221)
- Executive Committee, 6 Dec 1985 (Folder 221)
- Board Meeting, 7-8 Nov 1985 (Folder 221)
- Executive Committee, 2 Apr -1985 (Folder 221)
- Executive Committee, Metrop Club, 9 Dec 1983 (Folder 221)
- 7th Annual Board Mtg and Executive Committee, 11 Nov 1983 (Folder 221)
- CPD Meetings (Folder 221)
- CPD Briefing, 11 Jan 1979 (Folder 221)
- Think tank reports and booklets (Folder 222)
- Think tank reports and booklets (Folder 223)
- Carlucci, Frank (Folder 223)
- Carter (Folder 223)
- Carter Administration, JCS Military (Folder 224)
- Carter officials, Haig, 1983 (Folder 224)
- Haig, Alexander M. Jr., 1982 (Folder 225)
- Haig, 1980-1981 (Folder 225)
- Fred Charle Iklé (Folder 226)
- Kirpatrick, Jeane J. (Folder 226)
- Lehman, John, Secretary of the Navy (Folder 227)
- Marshall, Charles Burton (Folder 227)
- Meese, Ed (Folder 227)
- Mondale (Folder 228)
- Muskie (Folder 228)
- Why Compliance Matters, drafts of title reviewed by David Trachtenberg (Folder 229)
- The Dynamics of Domestic Policy and Arms Control-The SALT II Treaty Ratification Debate, Photocopy of Dan Caldwell's book, University of South Carolina Press, 1991 (Folder 229)
- Briefing charts and graphics on U.S. / Soviet ABM compared and Krasnoiarsk (Folder 229)
- Current News issues (Folder 230)
- Official documents (Folder 230)
- Official and think tank material (Folder 231)
- Videotape in an envelope (Folder 231)
- Current News issues (Folder 232)
- Loose material, mainly booklets, including a book pubished by the Institute of American Relations, SALT I Reconsidered-The Debate Over Ratification of the SALT I Treaty and Its Relevance Today, A Documentary Sourcebook with a Special Introduction by U.S. (Folder 233)
- Similar booklets (Folder 234)
- Documents on arms control and glasnost (David Trachtenberg) (Folder 235)
- SAT Conference at SMSU, including documents on W. Van Cleave (Folder 235)
- David Trachtenberg appearances in the media and in conferences (16 folders), 1984-1991 (Folder 236)
- David Trachtenberg appearances in the media and in conferences (17 folders), 1982-1984 (Folder 237)
- David Trachtenberg appearances in the media and in conferences (12 folders), 1981-1982 (Folder 238)
- Suzanne Crow (worked for CPD), 1987-1988 (Folder 239)
- Barbara Ann Perreault (Folder 239)
- Resumes, personnel (Folder 239)
- Receptionist (Folder 239)
- Tarver (Folder 239)
- DT resumes (Folder 239)
- Polls, 1978 (Folder 239)
- Congressional Elections, 1978 (Folder 239)
- Public Opinion Polls, 1979 (Folder 240)
- Polls, 1980 (Folder 240)
- Political polls, 1981 (Folder 240)
- Political polls, 1982-1984 (Folder 241)
- Political polls, 1985-1990 (Folder 242)
- Political polls, 1988 (Folder 243)
- Kissinger (Folder 243)
- Resumes (Folder 243)
- Kissinger, 1979-1981 (Folder 244)
- Kissinger, 1982-1992 (Folder 244)
- Krauthammer, Charles, April 1989 (Folder 244)
- K, mainly on Kissinger, 1974-1975 (Folder 244)
- David Trachtenberg files on various people including articles and sometimes correspondence (20 folders) (Folder 245)
- Michael Deaver (Folder 246)
- Courter / Wallop (Folder 246)
- Roger Barnett (Folder 246)
- Committee Rules (Folder 246)
- Graham Allison (Folder 246)
- Buchanan (Folder 246)
- Buckley (Folder 246)
- Cahill (Folder 246)
- Chayes (Folder 246)
- Kent C. Cooper (Folder 246)
- [charles kupperman] (Folder 247)
- Budget databases (Folder 247)
- Freeman Dyson-New Yorker series (Folder 247)
- MIRV (Folder 247)
- brochures by CPD: Peace With Freedom, 14 March 1978, Where We Stand on SALT, 11 November 1976, Public Attitudes on SALT II-The Results of a Nationwide Scientific Poll of American Opinion, 15 March 1979 (Folder 247)
- CPD Testimony before Congress (Folder 247)
- CPD draft papers, including a draft annotated copies of W. Scott Thompson, The North-South and East-West Connection, including a letter by Rostow, 6 June 1978 (Folder 247)
- Proposal for CPD Media Education Project 20 March 1978 (Folder 247)
- Foundations Grant Applications, including documents on applications to foundations for a continuing study on U.S.-Soviet Military balance, in 1978 (see box 219) (Folder 247)
- FIAT, contains personnal material on Kupperman's car breakdown (Folder 247)
- Gov. Edmund G. "Jerry" Brown (Folder 248)
- John Connally (Folder 248)
- Philip M. Crane (Folder 248)
- Howard Baker (Folder 248)
- Robert Dole (Folder 248)
- Gerald R. Ford (Folder 248)
- SALT II, Gen. Alexander M. Haig (Retired) (Folder 248)
- Kupperman correspondence, 1981 (Folder 248)
- Kupperman correspondence, 1980 (Folder 248)
- Kupperman article for World Press Review (Canada) (Folder 248)
- Talbott (Folder 248)
- Williams (Folder 248)
- R. James Woolsey (Folder 248)
- Yost, Sullivan drafts (Folder 248)
- Weiss (Folder 248)
- Scowcroft (Folder 248)
- Kupperman compiled materials on various people, R-S (12 folders) (Folder 249)
- Kupperman compiled materials on various people, K-P (7 folders) (Folder 250)
- Pipe's Material (Folder 250)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials (Folder 250)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials (Folder 251)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials, including rubber stamps and seal machine (Folder 252)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials and books (Folder 253)
- Peddlers of Crisis by Jerry Sanders (Folder 254)
- Senators P-Z, loose typed notes (27 folders) (Folder 254)
- (back to David Trachtenberg) (Folder 255)
- Correspondence including an audiotape from Radio America (Folder 255)
- Ferraro-Zaccaro (Folder 255)
- 1984 Campaign-Editorials / Op-eds (Folder 256)
- Endorsements (Folder 256)
- Reagan-Mondale debate 7 October 1984 (Folder 256)
- Voting records (Folder 257)
- Mondale campaign materials, march 1982- June 1984 (Folder 257)
- 1984 campaign materials (Folder 258)
- 1984 campaign materials (Folder 259)
- SALT II, Senate Armed Services Committee hearings: 23 July-3 August 1979 (Folder 260)
- SALT II, Senate Armed Services Committee HEARINGS: 23 July-9 October 1979 (Folder 260)
- SALT II, Senate Armed Services Committee Newspaper Coverage (Folder 260)
- 1984 campaign materials (Folder 261)
- SALT II, Senate Foreign Relations Committee, CPD Testimony (Folder 261)
- SALT II, Senate Foreign Relations Committee, markup (Folder 261)
- SALT II, Senate Armed Services Committee Newspaper Coverage (Folder 261)
- SALT II, Senate Foreign Relations Committee Report (Folder 262)
- SALT II, Senate Foreign Relations Committee, Brown Briefing, Fiscal Year 1981 Defense Budget, 13 December 1979 (Folder 262)
- Carter administration, Department of State publications (Folder 262)
- Carter administration, Department of State "Current Policy" (Folder 262)
- Carter administration, 1980 (Folder 263)
- Carter, State of the Union, 1981 (Folder 263)
- Carter, State of the Union, 1980 (Folder 263)
- Carter administration, 1979 (Folder 263)
- 1986 Elections (Folder 263)
- John F. Kennedy Campaign and Presidency, 1960 (Folder 263)
- Reagan General (Folder 263)
- 1980 Campaign, economic and spending issues (Folder 263)
- Defense budget and deficit (Folder 264)
- START paper (Folder 264)
- Executive Committee Agenda and Notices, 1980. Includes draft for America Is Becoming Number Two: The Growing Military Imbalance, 18 June 1980 (Folder 264)
- Executive Committee Agenda and Notices, 16 February and 23 March 1979 (Folder 265)
- Executive Committee Calls and Agenda, 1976-1977. Contains correspondence and material on meetings spring 1976-1977. See also box 298 (Folder 266)
- Executive Committee correspondence and materials, 1978 (Folder 266)
- CDP polls, 1984-1987 (Folder 267)
- Loose Material, 1978 (Folder 267)
- Loose material, 1990-1992 (Folder 267)
- Americans Talk Security: A Series of Surveys of American Voters, Attitudes concerning National Security Issues, November 1987-September 1990 (Folder 268)
- Trends in the U.S. / Soviet Military Balance: A Present Danger?, rough draft by F.P. Hoeber, 8 September and 10 October 1977 (Folder 269)
- CPD Personnel applicants (Folder 269)
- #13: "Public Attitudes on SALT II," 15 Mar 1979 (Folder 270)
- #14: "Is SALT II a Fair Deal for the United States?" (Folder 270)
- #15: "Why the Soviet Union Wants SALT II," 17 Sep 1979 (Folder 270)
- #16: "The Third Year as Reflected in the Media," Nov-79 (Folder 270)
- Paul H Nitze remarks and statement, Air War College, 18 May 77 (Folder 270)
- #12: "Does The Official Case For The Salt II Treaty Hold Up Under Analysis?" 14 Mar 1979 (Folder 271)
- #10: "The Second Year as Reflected in the Media," 1 Nov 1978 (Folder 271)
- #11: "Looking For Eggs In A Cuckoo Clock-Observations On Salt II" (Folder 271)
- "SALT II-A Soft Bargain, A Hard Sell-An Assessment of SALT in Historical Perspective," by Eugene Rostow, 1 Jul 1978 (Folder 271)
- "Is America Becoming Number Two?" proofs in an envelope (Folder 271)
- "Trends in the U.S. / Soviet Military Balance: A Present Danger?" draft copies of penultimate version, by F.P. Hoeber, 2 Feb 1978 (Folder 272)
- "Is America Becoming Number Two? Current Trends in the U.S.-Soviet Military Balance," copy and press release, 5 Oct 1978 (Folder 272)
- Present Danger balance sheet, 11 July 1978. Contains material on Hoeber and Trends in the U.S.-Soviet Military Balance (Folder 272)
- New York Times Magazine main article featuring Nitze and Kennan off-prints, 7 May 1978 (Folder 272)
- #8: "Peace with Freedom, A Discussion by the CPD Before the Foreign Policy Association," 14 Mar 1978 (Folder 272)
- Memo of conversation of Nitze, Zumwalt and Landon Butler, deputy assistant at the White House, 11 Jul 1978 (Folder 273)
- "Where We Stand on SALT" loose materials (Folder 273)
- SALT Legislative History. contains material re "Where We Stand on SALT" (Folder 273)
- #5: What the Media said about 'What IS the Soviet Union Up to?' 1 Aug 1977 (Folder 273)
- #7: Where We Stand... Summaries of Policy Statements 1976-1977, 1 Feb 1978 (Folder 273)
- #2: How the Committee on the Present Danger Will Operate-What It Will Do, and What It Will Not Do, 1 Sep 1976 (Folder 274)
- #3: The Nation's Editors Speak Up On 'The Present Danger,' with a Section on Soviet Reaction, Feb 1977 (Folder 274)
- #4: "What Is the Soviet Union Up To?" 4 Apr 1977 (Folder 274)
- Inventories of publications, February 1989, June 1987 (Folder 275)
- #1: "Common Sense and the Common Danger," 1 Nov 1976 (Folder 275)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam binder (Folder 276)
- Loose material, early 1990s (Folder 276)
- Committee issues analysis of Russian military expenditures press release, 24 Apr 1991 (Folder 276)
- CPD brochures and various newsletters, including a letter about articles and books on CPD (Folder 277)
- Newsletters, brochures, annual reports (Folder 278)
- Newsletters and magazines, and two polls by CPD (Folder 279)
- Phone directories and other materials (Folder 208)
- Loose materials (Folder 281)
- D, includes correspondance with people whose name begins with a D, including Midge Decter (Folder 282)
- C. Douglas Dillon (Folder 282)
- E (Folder 282)
- F (Folder 282)
- Henry H. Fowler (Folder 282)
- Andres Goodpaster (Folder 282)
- CPD, James T. Farrell (Folder 282)
- Ikle Subcommittee, The Propaganda Battle in the World (Folder 282)
- Adda B. Bozeman (Folder 283)
- W. Glenn Campbell (Folder 283)
- C (Folder 283)
- CPD: Board Names (Folder 284)
- Correspondence concerning Board (Folder 284)
- CPD Board, proposed for membership (Folder 284)
- Present Danger, Declines. (Folder 284)
- Loose material of 1976, including lists from which names for Board seem to have been picked (Folder 284)
- A (Folder 284)
- B, including CPD Board: (Folder 284)
- Frank R. Barnett (Folder 284)
- Dr. Donald G. Brennan (Folder 284)
- Attendance to Annual meeting cardboards (Folder 285)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials (Folder 286)
- CPD, Foreign policy association appearance, 14 Mar 1978 (Folder 287)
- CPD, Foreign relations committee appearance (cancelled), 13 Mar 1978 (Folder 287)
- SALT Nitze press conference #4, 24 Jul 1978 (Folder 287)
- CPD, breakfast meetings, 1 May 1978 (Folder 287)
- Nitze evaluation, 29 Sep 1978 (Folder 287)
- Is America Becoming Number Two? press confrence, 5 Sep 1978 (Folder 287)
- Women's organizations representatives briefing, 9 Mar 1979 (Folder 287)
- Nitze SALT press conference, 14 Dec 1978. Contains attachments: Current SALT II Negotiating Posture based on Where We Stand On SALT and Nize's subsequent series of papers on the SALT II negotiations which were released on 1 November 1977, 28 March 1978, and 24 July 1978 (Folder 287)
- Service organizations Sulgrave briefing, 1 Jan 1979 (Folder 287)
- Nitze, HR Armed services committee, 6 Feb 1979 (Folder 287)
- Nitze, SALT Release, 9 March 1979. Contains an updated copy, Current SALT II Negotiating Posture, 9 March 1979 (Folder 287)
- Press interviews (Folder 287)
- Present Danger press releases, 11 Nov 1976 (Folder 288)
- Present Danger, SALT press conference, 6 Jul 1977 (Folder 288)
- Present Danger, Initial press conference, 11 November 1976. Includes transcript of the press conference (Folder 288)
- What is the Soviet Union up to? press conference, 6 Jul 1977 (Folder 288)
- CPD, SALT press conference, 1 Nov. 1977. Includes a letter by Jeremy Stone complaining about Nitze's leaks (Folder 288)
- CPD, SALT-White House Conference 4 Aug 1977 (Folder 288)
- Current SALT II Negotiating posture, draft by Nitze, 2 Feb 1978 (Folder 288)
- CPD SALT II press conference, #3 Paul H. Nitze, 28 Mar 1978. Includes transcript (Folder 288)
- Senate budget hearing, Rostow, 1 Mar 1978 (Folder 288)
- CPD dinner meeting, 7 Jun 1988 (Folder 289)
- Meetings and interviews, 1984-1988-1989. Includes lists of interviews given by David Trachtenberg (Folder 289)
- Colleges and High schools, requests for material and thank you notes (Folder 289)
- Meetings, Miscellaneous, 1981-1983 (Folder 289)
- Meetings, 1980 (Folder 289)
- Speaker requests (Folder 289)
- Appearances by Board members, 1978-1982 (Folder 289)
- Syllabi (Folder 289)
- Present Danger, Ernest W. Lefever (Folder 290)
- M [and L] (Folder 290)
- CPD board, Gerald M. Mayer (Folder 290)
- Max M. Kampelman (2 folders) (Folder 291)
- K, including Keyserling (Folder 291)
- Jeanne J. Kirkpatrick, letters to her (Folder 291)
- J (Folder 291)
- Lane Kirkland (Folder 291)
- CPD drafts (Folder 292)
- Inquiry responses, WM. Moon and others (Folder 292)
- Speaker inquiries (Folder 292)
- Education (Folder 292)
- Publication Strategic Arms Control in the Reagan Administration: A Chronology of Events Taken From Published Source Materials (Folder 293)
- Office business (Folder 293)
- Presentations (Folder 293)
- CPD papers (Folder 293)
- Conference (Folder 293)
- Public relations (Folder 293)
- Defense strategy and funding for 1980 press conference, 9 May 1980 (Folder 294)
- The 1980 Crisis, press conference, 23 January 1980. Contains transcript including Rostow, Nitze, Fowler, and Pipes (Folder 294)
- "Has America Become Number Two?" Press conference, 29 Jun 1982 (Folder 294)
- State of the Union press release, 6 Feb 1980 (Folder 294)
- Reagan Defense program press conference, 17 Mar 1982. Includes brochure "Is the Reagan Defense Program Adequate?" (Folder 294)
- CPD statements and press releases: Polls, 1985-1988 (Folder 294)
- Defense for everyone by Edward Teller (Folder 294)
- Clippings (Folder 294)
- Seminar and Edward Teller Dinner, 10th anniversary-dinner with Teller, 1 Oct 1986 (Folder 294)
- Annual Meeting, 1986 (Folder 294)
- Contributors, new contributors, monthly reports, and records of deceased (Folder 294)
- CPD statements, CPD clips, and various documents (Folder 295)
- NBC Debate (Folder 295)
- Nitze speeches (Folder 296)
- Speaking engagements (Folder 296)
- Radio and TV appearances (Folder 296)
- Nitze Press Conferences, July 24, 1978-October 5, 1978.Includes transcripts of Rostow, Nitze and Pipes (Folder 296)
- Poll press conference, Nitze and Connell, 15 Mar 1979 (Folder 296)
- SALT II Nitze press conference, 23 April 1979. Contains an updated copy of Current SALT II Negotiating Posture by Nitze, 23 April 1979 (Folder 296)
- Senate foreign relations committee, 1979. Includes Nitze, Rostow and Pipes materials (Folder 296)
- Nitze press conference, 19 Jul 1979 (Folder 296)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials (Folder 297)
- Citizens Committe for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam materials (Folder 298)
- Rostow materials, October-November 1976 (Folder 298)
- Information on office files-CPD index, 14 Jun 1982 (Folder 299)
- Burrell's press clipping service, 1991 (Folder 299)
- Courier services (Folder 299)
- EBM (Folder 299)
- Mailings, 1988 (Folder 299)
- Office supplies, 1986 (Folder 299)
- Mark J. Penn, Penn and Schoen Associates, Inc. (Folder 299)
- Printing, Tyler Business Services, 1986- (Folder 299)
- Rigdwells (Folder 299)
- Sulgrave Club (Folder 299)
- United Parcel Service (Folder 299)
- Telephone and subscriptions records (Folder 300)
- Xerox machines records (Folder 301)
- David Trachtenberg, Correspondence with Journalists, 1980's (Folder 302)
- May, 1979 (Folder 302)
- Correspondence with executive committe members (Folder 302)
- Correpondence (Folder 302)
- Appearances, interviews, meetings, phone conversations (Folder 302)
- CPD materials requests (Folder 302)
- David Trachtenberg materials on an op-ed refused by various newspapers (Folder 302)
- Military balance in 1985, Jodd (Folder 303)
- SART-INF merger (Folder 303)
- Weighing Mr. Bundy's Pause Washington Post opinion publique, Sept 1983 (Folder 303)
- How to Get a Good Arms Treaty (Folder 303)
- National Review, letter to the editor (Folder 303)
- Cold shoulder for the freeze ROA (Folder 303)
- Interdependent Article (Folder 303)
- Op-ed pieces (Folder 303)
- Trachtenberg, David, articles and op-eds (published or unpublished) (Folder 304-306)
- Loose issues of Orbis (Folder 307)
- Loose issues of Orbis (Folder 308)
- Soviet Statements, 1977-1982 (Folder 308)
- Soviet Statements, 1983-1985 (Folder 309)
- Soviet Statements, 1986-1988 (Folder 310)
- Soviet Statements, 1989- (Folder 311)
- Non-compliance reports (Folder 311)
- U.S. non-compliance, 1986-1987 (Folder 312)
- Soviet non-compliance, 1988- (Folder 312)
- Chernobyl (Folder 312)